https://www.ritchiebros.com/privacy-statement

Privacy Statement
Effective as of February 27, 2020.
Logging
in to IronPlanet's online marketplaces using your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers web
account
Logging
in to a preferred provider's site using Ritchie Bros. credentials
Being
the trusted choice for your global asset management and disposition needs
starts with Ritchie Bros.' unrivaled commitment to customer service.  As part of that commitment, we respect the
privacy of our customers and users.
Whether we are helping to appraise, sell, inspect, buy, refurbish, transport
or finance your heavy equipment, trucks, and other assets around the world, we
are guided by our desire to meet your needs in a convenient, fair and
transparent manner – and that includes making sure you understand how we handle
personal information and what corresponding rights are available to you.
Ritchie
Bros. is a global organization with companies located around the world that
operate our multi-channel solutions for buying and selling, as well as our
related service offerings. Our brand solutions include:
This
Privacy Statement applies to ritchiebros.com and other Ritchie Bros. websites,
services and solutions that collect information and display or link to this
Statement, and that are owned and operated by a member of the Ritchie Bros.
group of companies.  This Privacy
Statement does not apply if the Ritchie Bros. website, service or solution does
not display or link to it or where the website, service or solution makes its
own privacy notice available.  This
Privacy Statement applies equally to our digital handling of your information
as it does to our offline collection and handling.
To
understand which Ritchie Bros. company is responsible for the collection and
further processing of your personal information, see the section below entitled
"Data Controllers".
We
may change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting the revised statement
on this website and indicating the effective date of the revised
statement.  The revised Privacy Statement
will be effective once posted unless we state otherwise.
We
may also supplement or modify our privacy commitments in this Privacy Statement
through other notices we make available to you or through contractual
commitments we enter in writing.
Where
we've provided a translation of the English language version of this Privacy
Statement, such translation is provided for your convenience only.  To the extent there is any inconsistency
between the English language version and such translation, the English language
version takes precedence.
2. Who to contact with questions or for more
information
If
you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement or our
practices, you can reach our Data Protection Officer through our Data Privacy
Office at:
Or use our privacy
contact form.
3. What personal information we collect and
process
Our
multiple solutions are designed to help your business Move, Build and Grow.
Most
of the information we collect, and process, is equipment related information
and business contact information relating to, and provided by, our customers'
employees or other workers.  In general,
information is collected when a customer engages one of our brand solutions to
provide services by entering a contract, creating an online account, coming
into one of our auction locations to register for an auction, providing us
information through a webform, or otherwise interacting with us.  Information may also be obtained from other
sources.  For instance, brand solutions
may share information, or an outside service provider is used to verify or supplement
what we've received.  In some cases, the
information we obtain is generated automatically when users engage with our
digital services, such as browsing our websites, using our mobile applications,
opening our communications or clicking on our advertisements.
While
our solutions are generally not targeted at individuals buying or selling for
personal, family or household purposes, individuals do engage with certain of
our solutions from time to time for these purposes.
Some
information we obtain from you may be more sensitive in nature and depends on
the services you are engaging us to perform.
For instance, we may require ID numbers from a driver's license or other
identity documentation to process transactions or facilitate the extension of
financing to your business. Some of this information may be considered more
sensitive in nature.
Certain
of our brand solutions obtain and store personal information for the benefit of
our corporate or government customers to provide those customers specific technology
services.  In those circumstances, we are
acting as a service provider and collect and process that information in
accordance with our customers written instructions and our contractual arrangement.
Offering
you the choice of multiple solutions for different needs means that each
solution operates somewhat differently.
To learn more about the categories of information handled by specific
solutions and their sources, read on.
3.1 Core asset disposition services
Our
core asset disposition services include:
Brand
Details of Offering
Offers
unreserved public auctions with onsite and online bidding, as well as other non-auction-related
services (e.g. RB Logistics, private treaty, appraisal, inspections)
Offers an
online only marketplace with featured weekly online unreserved auctions
Provides
access to the MarketPlace-E online platform
Powers
sector-specific solutions GovPlanet, TruckPlanet and Salvage Sale and provides
the online auction platform to support online bidding at Kruse Energy and Leake
Auction sales events
Since you are required to have an IronPlanet
account to use these specific solutions or to bid online, the categories of personal
information collected, and sources, are the same
Operates
an online public listing marketplace available on the web or through a mobile
app where buyers and sellers can post ads and communicate with each other about
equipment advertised
Offers
auction and private treaty services tailored to the energy industry
The
list below describes examples of the collection and processing of personal
information by category and source for the core asset disposition services.
Check marks indicate the relevant brand practices.
Note
that since online bidding and private treaty sales for Kruse Energy and Leake
Auction are facilitated through, and managed and supported by, IronPlanet's
online auction platform, bidders and sellers (in the case of private treaty) must
first create an IronPlanet account.
Accordingly, the information collected automatically (including through
cookies or other similar tools) as identified under "IronPlanet" in the list below
applies equally for Kruse and Leake online bidders and buyers.
Category: Account Registration Data
Description:
Data that identifies you – name, title, employment status, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses, account password and in some cases, personal ID document numbers (driver’s license, passport, national or state identity card, or SSN), age, nationality, tax identification numbers, and your signature
Sources:
Personal information you provide when buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services (appraisals, inspections, shipping, logistics, or repair & refurbishment), creating or updating an account or otherwise interacting with us
Information from your business colleagues or partners who add you to their online account
Personal Information contained on motor vehicle titles and other equipment registration documents we handle in a transaction
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Sources:
Personal information you provide when posting an ad on the marketplace, inquiring about a seller’s item, registering for an account or otherwise interacting with us
Information from your organization who posts equipment ads on the marketplace
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information from third-party business data providers or publicly available sources to supplement our sales leads and prospects
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Data needed to complete a check of the US Federal System for Award Management and an End User Certificate facilitating the transfer of an asset to a party outside the US Department of Defense – name, social security number or other personal ID number, date of birth, place of birth, telephone number, address, purpose of buying, signature and if applicable, their role as officer, partner or agent with the purchaser
Source:
Information US individuals provide when registering an account to bid and when buying certain GovPlanet equipment
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Social security number along with other identifying information on tax exemption forms
Source:
Personal information you provide when relying on a tax exemption for purchases of a sole proprietorship
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Transaction Data
Description:
Data regarding self-listings, bids, purchases, or sales in a transaction
Sources:
Personal information you provide when listing, buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services or otherwise interacting with us
Information collected automatically when you use our websites, mobile apps and webservices to bid or buy
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information from other solutions operated by members of the Ritchie Bros. group of companies
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Data regarding your online purchase of tickets to our auction events
Source:
Information from our third-party service providers managing the sale of tickets to our events and processing ticket payments
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Payment Data
Description:
Banking information (account numbers and payment details) and credit card information necessary to process a bidding deposit or transaction
Source:
Personal information you provide when listing, buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services, creating or updating an account or otherwise interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Payment information (account numbers and payment details) and credit card information necessary to process ad placements or other services
Source:
Personal information you provide when posting an ad on the marketplace or entering into a listing contract
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Shipping and Logistics Data
Description:
Shipping, billing, and other information you provide in connection with the purchase or shipping of an asset, as well as information required for bills of lading or customs clearance (such as tax identification numbers or other identification numbers)
Source:
Personal information you provide when listing, buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services or otherwise interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Industry Preference, Interest and Feedback Data
Description:
Data regarding industry and equipment interests and preferences or assets you wish to value or sell when you complete a webform, engage with us on social media or at tradeshows, or participate in surveys, feedback forms, our online community discussion platform, contests and focus groups
Source:
Personal information you provide when interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Customer Service Data
Description:
Information relating to inquiries about services, dispute resolution, and, where applicable, recorded customer service calls
Source:
Personal information you provide when interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Visitor and Incident Log Data
Description:
Log data collected in connection with your entering our physical offices or auction sites, or in the event of an incident (motor vehicle collision, injury or environmental event) you are involved in or witness while onsite
Source:
Personal information you provide when visiting our offices or auction sites
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
GovPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: CCTV Data
Description:
CCTV video footage at our physical offices and sites
Source:
Personal Information collected automatically when you visit our physical offices and sites
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
GovPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Online Account Usage Data
Description:
Data generated through actions you take which are linked to an online account, for instance when you create watchlists or saved searches, search inventory or results, change your communication and marketing preferences, register to bid or enter a Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers’ auction ring online, whether you bid or not (including assigned bidder numbers, bid amounts, winning bids), or register for bidding privileges on an IronPlanet marketplace
Source:
Information collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservice
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our online auction bidding engine service provider on our behalf
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Geolocation Data
Description:
Geolocation data, including that of your mobile device when you enable the use of location services in your device settings or in app
Source:
Information from your device collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Device Connection Data
Description:
Computer and other device connection data, such as page view statistics, data traffic to and from websites, referral URL, your IP address, access times, browser, language settings and web server log information
Source:
Information from your device we collect automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices, and in some cases, using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Model or device type, operating system and version, browser type and settings, device ID or individual device identifier, advertisement ID, cookie ID, or IP address from which the device accessed our services
Source:
Information from your device collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our electronic signature solution service provider on our behalf when interacting with contractual and related documents we send to you
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Online Activity Data
Description:
Webpages of ours you visit, time of access, frequency and duration of visits, the links you click or other actions you take as part of your use of the website or mobile app
Source:
Information collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Information about your activities and interactions with sponsored or featured digital advertising content or our marketing emails, such as advertisements you were shown, when and where they were shown, and whether you clicked and took any subsequent action like filling out a webform or telephoning a seller on Mascus about their equipment
Source:
Information from our advertising and analytical service providers collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our phone call analytics service provider on our behalf when you call us at a phone number (displayed for instance on our marketing landing pages or webforms)
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our phone call analytics service provider on our behalf when you call a seller at the phone number displayed on the ad listing page
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
For
further information about the collection of data using cookies, web beacons and
similar tools when you interact with our digital services, such as website or
email communications, interact with advertisements or initiate certain
telephone calls, check out "Cookies & similar
technologies and your preferences" below.
We
combine or link the personal information we collect from you with information we
receive from the other sources identified in the chart above. Where we receive
data from third parties, we try to confirm the information was lawfully collected
and disclosed to us.
IronPlanet's
other technology solutions – Marketplace Direct, Super Marketplace Direct, and
GovPlanet Direct –power the direct marketplaces of some of our corporate and
government customers.  To participate in
their online sales events, you must have an IronPlanet account.  We do not handle the exchange of funds or
otherwise participate in the closing of any transactions between you and our
direct marketplace customers.
Information regarding your bidding activity – user name, location, bids
placed – as a user of their direct marketplace is collected and made available
to our customers for use and handling in accordance with their respective
privacy policies.  As a service provider,
we do not use this information for our own commercial purposes other than to
perform the services of hosting and managing the functionality of the
marketplaces for our customers.  If you
have concerns about the use and handling of your information by these
customers, you will need to contact them directly.
Mascus
also provides tools for professionals to help manage their inventory,
understand the used equipment market, publish listings on the Mascus online
listing marketplace and reach bigger buying audiences.  Mascus' tools for professionals are part of
the suite of tools offered under the Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions brand.  Mascus systems power these tools for our
professional customers.  For more
information about the handling of personal information when interacting with
these tools, refer to the Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions section below.
3.2 Other asset disposition-related services
Our
other asset disposition-related services include:
Ritchie
Bros. Asset Solutions (RBAS) is a collection of tools – cloud-based inventory
management system (IMS), managed and hosted custom webshops, mobile apps for
inspection and inventory management, marketing tools and a data insights module
– that we make available to our OEM, corporate and government customers on a
subscription basis.  The tools are
configured for use by our customers' end users – both for their employees and
other personnel and for interested buyers of their equipment.
If
you are an RBAS customer, your end users need to understand how you (and we)
collect and process their personal information.
Accordingly, if you use a custom webshop or mobile app, you agree to
post an up-to-date and accurate privacy notice on those tools that complies
with the laws applicable to your business.
You also agree to obtain consent from your end users for the use and
access of their personal information by us and other third parties.
Except
as noted below, information about end users interacting with RBAS tools is
collected and processed by us as a processor on behalf of our customer in which
case we act on the instructions of, or as permitted by, our customer or their
authorized internal end users.  We don't
use the personal information we maintain about your end users who interact with
your custom webshop to independently contact or market to them.  If you are an end user and have questions or
concerns regarding the handling of your information, refer to the privacy
policies made available by our customer (who may be your employer) through the
relevant RBAS tool.
If
you are a representative of our corporate or government customer subscribing
for services, we collect your business contact information to establish and
maintain our relationship with our customer as their service provider (e.g.
customer service and invoicing).
We
also collect IMS end user credentials and interactions with the IMS to monitor,
log, analyze and test the security of the systems, networks, databases and
applications supporting the IMS and to ensure compliance by the customer with
our contractual arrangements.  We also
use this interaction data to monitor and improve the general performance and
usability of the IMS such as enhanced features, GUI layouts, and page
responsiveness.
Information
and data collected by us through management of RBAS tools will be used as
necessary to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.
Ritchie
Bros. Financial Services facilitates financing and leasing solutions for
auction customers and other equipment owners and dealers referred through our
partner networks.  We do not offer
financial products for personal, family or household purposes.  Personal information collected includes:
Category of Information
Description
Source(s)
Application
and Identity Data
Data
that identifies you as the principal or guarantor of a business applicant –
name, residential address, birthdate, gender, social insurance or security
number, phone numbers, email, ownership type and interest in the applicant,
shareholder or member registers
Personal
information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products,
inquiring about a credit approval or rejection, or otherwise interacting with
our account managers
Information from third-party business data
providers and publicly available sources to supplement leads and prospects
Application
and Identity Data
Identification
documentation including driver’s licenses, passports or other government ID (e.g.
social insurance or security number card)
Personal information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products or otherwise interacting with our account managers
Credit
and Financial Data
Current
and historical financial information, including tax returns, assessment
notices, void cheques, estimates of net worth and financial statements
Personal information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products or otherwise interacting with our account managers
Credit
and Financial Data
Credit bureau reports and other credit information
Information from credit reporting agencies and or credit grantors
Loan Approval Data
Data regarding a credit approval (e.g. the amount to be financed by a
lender partner) and other data associated with completion of a loan transaction
with a lender partner (e.g. financing documents)
regarding industry and equipment interests and preferences, assets you wish to purchase,
your business structure and financing or leasing needs
Information
you provide when applying for financial or insurance products or otherwise
interacting with our account managers
Online
Account Usage Data
User
data (e.g. account information, actions taken) relating to a user who creates a
watchlist on the Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or IronPlanet website
Information
from other solutions operated by members of the Ritchie Bros. group of
companies
Auction
Lead Data
Successful
buyer and runner-up bidder data (e.g. name, contact information, equipment bid
on and purchased, price) for auction buyers and bidders from other solutions
operated by members the Ritchie Bros. group of companies
Information
from other solutions operated by members of the Ritchie Bros. group of
companies
Referred Lead Data
Financing lead contact information and industry related information
Information from third party lead referral partners (for example,
publishers who advertise and promote our services
Online
Activity Data
Webpages
and webforms viewed or submitted, time of landing, frequency and duration of
viewing, the links you click or other actions you take as part of your use of
the website or interaction with our email
Information
from your device collected automatically when you browse the IronPlanet or
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers websites or fill out a webform using cookies, web
beacons and similar tools
Online
Activity Data
Information
about your activities and interactions with sponsored or featured digital
advertising content or our marketing emails, such as advertisements you were
shown, when and where they were shown, and whether you clicked and took any
subsequent action like filling out a webform or adding equipment to a watchlist
Information
from our advertising and analytical service providers collected automatically
when you browse equipment or login to the IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros.
Auctioneers websites or interact with our emails using cookies, web beacons and
similar tools
Device
Connection Data
Model
or device type, operating system and version, browser type and settings, device
ID or individual device identifier, advertisement ID, cookie ID, and IP address
from which the device accessed our services
Information
from your device collected automatically when you browse or login to the
IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers websites using cookies, web beacons and
similar tools
For
further information about the collection of data using cookies, web beacons and
similar tools when you interact with the Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or
IronPlanet website, our custom webforms or our email communications, check out "Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences"
below.
We
combine or link the personal information we collect from you with information
we receive from the other sources identified in the chart above. Where we
receive data from third parties, we try to confirm the information was lawfully
collected and disclosed to us.
4. Purposes and legal basis for handling your
information
We
use your personal information for a range of different business and other
purposes and according to different legal bases of processing.  We use information collected to primarily
provide solutions and services, to respond to requests about our solutions and
services, to protect our rights and the rights of others, to provide you with personalized
digital advertising and marketing, to provide customer service, to detect,
prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities, and to communicate
with you about your account and our solutions and services.  See the table below to learn more about
examples of our processing purposes.
a contract with you or your business entity for products and services for
publish and promote your assets, listings and related content on the websites,
marketplaces or in the applications of Ritchie Bros. multi-channel solutions or
External operators of websites, applications,
services and tools
To
register you to bid in-person at a live auction event and assign you a bidding
number; approve and monitor bidding limits or privileges on our transactional
solutions (including on GovPlanet after conducting a check in the US Federal
System for Award Management); and process bidding deposits or authorizations
where required after performing identity and address verification and credit
External operators of websites, applications,
services and tools
To
create an online account for you permitting you, and others added to your
account, to access our websites, applications and other tools across the
various Ritchie Bros. solutions, including the online bidding platform and
and perform online and offline auction transactions with us, including
processing motor vehicle titles or transfers of equipment requiring entry in
national registries more efficiently, collecting and paying fees or money owed
(including proving chain of ownership of assets to a buyer’s lender in order to
facilitate the lender’s financing of the auction sale), processing payments
(including processing tax exemptions and refunds), and connecting IronPlanet
marketplace sellers and buyers to facilitate the pick-up and release of items
(including in cases of terminated, failed or subsequently voided transactions),
or to connect Mascus marketplace advertisers and interested buyers to
provide auction-related and value-added services, including completing
appraisals or inspections, arranging for transportation and insurance of your
assets or extended warranties, assisting with export and import of assets,
storing of your assets, facilitating repair and refurbishment of assets with
External operators of websites, applications,
services and tools
To enable
you to use certain services (ours or a cooperating third party) or make
available functionality of our websites applications and tools where you
request them, including processing geolocation data to provide you with
External operators of websites, applications,
services and tools
To
conduct credit checks by pulling credit reports and other credit information to
assess creditworthiness and facilitate credit approvals or the leasing or
party operators of websites, applications, services and tools we cooperate with
Lending and financial product partners whom we
work with to provide financing and leasing products and services
To communicate
with you, either directly or through a cooperating third party, about:
account
issues and warnings – e.g. dispute resolution, other customer service items,
data privacy requests, cybersecurity events
service
functionality – e.g. outages, saved searches, watchlist items, missed buyer
inquires on Mascus and ad alerts
transactions
– e.g. consignments, listings, sales, purchases, recall
notices from Original Equipment Manufacturers (OEMs) and dealers
marketing
collateral – e.g. emails from members of the Ritchie Bros. group about sales
events, equipment, events and other offers from Ritchie Bros. multiple
solutions
research
– e.g. opinion polls or surveys
promotions
– e.g. phone calls about available equipment or other items for sale, or to offer
financing or leasing products and services offered by Ritchie Bros. Financial
Services or other financing service providers
via emails, phone calls, mail, notifications, or
other messages (e.g. SMS or WhatsApp), consistent with any permissions you have
conduct research and surveys, gather feedback, facilitate your participation in
contests and sweepstakes, create marketing collateral using your image or
our rights, reputation, safety and property, or that of third parties, including:
by
recording and analyzing CCTV footage of our physical offices and auction sites,
and
tracking details of attendees and others
visiting our auction sites (e.g. to inspect or transport assets)
enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
External
professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To
participate in proceedings conducted by courts, public agencies or authorities,
law enforcement, or other public bodies if there is a legal obligation to this
effect or we legitimately consider disclosure of information is necessary to
enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
To prevent,
detect, mitigate, investigate and take action against fraud, security breaches
and other prohibited or unlawful activities (e.g. money laundering and
terrorist financing), or the violation of our contacts and other policies,
including the assessment of corresponding risks, by for example:
the
use of captchas or telephone number verification)
monitoring
account activity
conducting
screening of global sanctions lists to prevent the trade of equipment or other
items with embargoed countries, designated persons or entities
reviewing bill of lading and other documentation
to ensure buyers of assets through our transactional solutions are not
enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
comply with subpoenas, warrants or other legal processes or to cooperate with
government or public authorities' or agencies' inspections or investigations,
or protect the interests of a third party involved in legal disputes if we legitimately
consider disclosure of information is necessary to avert severe disadvantages
enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
monitor and improve the information security of systems, applications and tools
keep complete and accurate financial records of our transactions and trade
record customer service calls for internal training and dispute resolution
analyze and troubleshoot errors, crashes or bugs that relate to our systems and
applications to remedy issues or to make our user experience better, or to test
To personalize,
measure the quality and success of, deliver and improve our emails, digital
advertisements and content in the online offerings of members of the Ritchie
Bros. group of companies or those of third parties across the web, including:
contextual
personalization based on user interactions with our online offerings or after
considering other information we have about a user
tracking
calls placed to us for products and services and combine with the user's other
interactions with our websites or webforms
combining
and analyzing insight reports using data about user transaction history,
patterns of usage of our websites or after combining user information with data
relating to your use of services we provide (e.g. to understand the secondary
equipment market and develop new products, services or features)
tracking usage of Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers' or
IronPlanet's websites (such as creation of equipment watchlists or saved
searches) and interaction with Ritchie Bros. Financial Services' email
track whether a call is placed to a seller advertising assets for sale on the
Mascus marketplace to analyze buyer activity and combine with the user's other
internet activity on the marketplace to generate buyer insight reports and
To facilitate sellers' compliance with legal obligations,
including:
supplying to California sellers a list of
buyers for their assets to facilitate compliance with California Air Resources
Board record keeping requirements
sharing with
government or public agency sellers lists of bidders for their assets to
facilitate compliance with federal, state or municipal bylaws, rules or
facilitate OEMs and their dealers understanding the secondary market for their
equipment and their communication with bidders and buyers at Ritchie Bros.
Auctioneers and IronPlanet sales events about warranties, parts and other
products and services.
analyze and generate leads and prospects for financing and other services for
enhance, categorize and prioritize financing leads, prospects and applicants
and score them based on predicted readiness to bid or buy, type of borrower and
creditworthiness (including by sharing limited non-personal information with
external service providers specializing in aggregating business credit data and
supplying business credit reports)
comply with audit obligations under our contractual arrangements with financing
operators of websites, applications, services and tools whom we have a referral
arrangement
To
initiate, prepare for and execute a business change, e.g. in the event of a
merger with another company, sale of assets, joint venture, reorganization,
bankruptcy or takeover by another company, including to negotiate and permit
due diligence of the transaction and to plan for and execute integration
you make a bid during a Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or an IronPlanet sales event,
we may share your bid and contact information with the OEM of the lot you bid
on and any of the OEM's dealers or representatives in your geographic area, if
the OEM or dealer/representative entered into a contractual arrangement with us.
We do not trade this information in
exchange for money.  OEMs and their
dealers or representatives use this information to pursue their legitimate
interest of understanding the lifecycle of their equipment and the secondary
market for their equipment, to communicate with you about their products and
services, and for other purposes disclosed in their privacy policies. Once
disclosed, this information will be governed by the OEM's or the OEM dealer's
privacy policy and will be subject to the laws of the jurisdiction in which the
OEM or OEM dealer processes the information. See "Privacy related requests
and your preferences"
below on how to opt-out of this sharing and how to request which OEMs and
dealers your information was disclosed to during the 12-month period preceding
the date of your request.  For more
information, visit our "Data Handling and Sharing FAQ".
4.3 Data usage between Ritchie Bros. corporate
family members
In
pursuit of our common interests we permit access to personal information among
members of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family for purposes consistent with this
Privacy Statement. Where permitted by law, you may receive promotional and
other communications from these related family members.  See our
"Data Handling and Sharing FAQ" for
more information.  To the extent that Ritchie
Bros. corporate family members have access to your personal information, they
will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices
described in this Privacy Statement.
4.4 Automated decision-making
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers and IronPlanet use automated
decision-making technologies to assist in determining a user's bidding
privileges and whether a deposit is required prior to bidding.  This processing assists us in protecting our
interests and the integrity of our auctions and efficiently make decisions to
extend to you the contractual right to bid at an auction.  Our decision on bidding privileges or a
deposit may be reviewed by a Customer Care agent.
5. International transfer
Data
we collect is transferred to database servers located in various regions,
including Canada, European member states, Serbia and the United States. In
addition, our personnel and our third-party service providers whom we transfer
your information to for our business purposes may also store and access (and in
the case of service providers, onward transfer to) your personal information in
other countries. These countries may offer a different level of data protection
and may have different data protection rules than your country of residence. In
certain circumstances courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or
security authorities in those other foreign jurisdictions may be entitled to
access your information.
Under
the General Data
Protection Regulation (GDPR)
and other data protection laws, information about individuals who are entitled
to protection under those laws may only be transferred from their region to
other regions if certain requirements are met.
When we transfer your personal information from outside the EEA or UK,
we rely on a variety of measures to support the transfer under EU or UK law, as
applicable. As the European Commission and UK government consider Canada to be
a country which provides adequate data protection, information may be
transferred from the EEA or UK to Canada.
In other cases, we may rely on a service provider's registration in the
EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield (if sent to the US) and/or contractual
means to require administrative and technological safeguards designed to
mitigate the threat of unauthorized access, use or disclosure of your
information (such as standard data protection clauses issued or approved by the
European Commission (2010/87/EU, 2001/497/EC or 2004/915/EC).  Please contact us if you have any questions
about the transmission of information among members of the Ritchie Bros.
corporate family or our transfers to service providers.
6. Storage and erasure
We
and our service providers store personal information in accordance with
applicable data protection laws to the extent necessary for the purposes set
out in this Privacy Statement or for which you are otherwise notified.  We will destroy or obfuscate data in
accordance with our data retention and deletion policy unless we are obliged to
keep your personal data longer (i.e. for legal or audit purposes).  In general, Ritchie Bros.' retention periods
are 7 years.  Permanent deletion of data
can be difficult due to the impact on applications and systems.  Where legally permissible, we may restrict further
access or usage of data instead of deleting it.
Retention
periods vary by region, the service or product in question and applicable law.  We consider the following factors:
Is the information necessary to provide the
service or product?  This covers things such as entering into a
contract with you, performing the service requested or paid for, or maintaining
appropriate business and financial records.
Is the information sensitive in nature?
What statutory, contractual or similar
obligations exist?  This covers things such as retaining
information as a result of contractual obligations or due to anticipated or
pending legal disputes.  Certain laws
also stipulate required retention periods for certain information.
What will the impact on the integrity of systems
and applications be if the information is removed?
7. Data security
While
we take reasonable administrative, technical and physical measures to protect
the information you submit or that we collect online and offline against loss,
theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, we cannot guarantee
its absolute security. No Internet, email or mobile application transmission is
ever fully secure or error free, nor are firewalls and physical access
restrictions impenetrable.
If
you believe your account has been abused, please contact us at customercare@ritchiebros.com.
8. Privacy related requests and your preferences
You may request to exercise the data subject rights described in this part by using
our dedicated privacy
contact form.  If you prefer, you can send correspondence to
Ritchie Bros., Attn: Data Privacy Office, 9500 Glenlyon
Parkway, Burnaby, British Columbia, Canada, V5J0C6, or call our Customer Service group.
California Residents.  If you
are a resident of California, see our State Privacy
Disclosures page for specific information on Your California
Privacy Rights.
Access to Information.  In some jurisdictions,
applicable law provides the right to be informed of and request access to the
personal information we hold and
process about you.  For instance,
for individuals with rights under the GDPR, you may request information on the
purposes of the processing, the categories of personal information concerned,
the categories of recipients to whom the personal information have been or will
be disclosed, the envisaged period for which the personal information will be
stored, the existence of the right to request rectification or erasure of
personal information or restriction of processing of personal information or to
object to such processing, the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory
authority, any available information as to the personal information's source
(where not collected from you), the existence of automated decision-making,
including profiling and, where appropriate, meaningful information on its
details.  Access to information may be subject to certain exemptions.
Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Data.  You have
the right to ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information
concerning you.  For certain services, you
may also use your online account profile page to review and edit some of your
personal information.
Data Portability.  For
individuals with rights under the GDPR, you may request personal information about
you, that you provided to us, be delivered to you in a structured, commonly
used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this
information to another service provider (where technically feasible).
Erasure.  You can request that we erase your personal
information and deactivate your applicable user account.  Please note that exemptions and restrictions
may apply depending on applicable law.
In some cases, we will not erase the data, but instead restrict further
processing (e.g. where the information is still necessary in relation to the purpose
for which it was collected or is needed to establish, exercise or defend a
legal claim).  We may also obfuscate/pseudonymize
or aggregate data where permitted.
Withdrawing Consent.  Where
you have provided your consent to our processing of your personal information
you may withdraw your consent at any time.
Please specify if the request is a general withdrawal or which specific consent
you want to withdraw. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not
affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before
its withdrawal.
Restricting Processing. In some jurisdictions, applicable law may give
you the right to restrict the ways in which we use your personal information.
For instance, under the GDPR, where:
you
contest the accuracy of your personal information;
the
processing is unlawful but you oppose the erasure of your personal information;
we
no longer need your personal information for the purposes of the processing,
but you require the information for the establishment, exercise or defence of
legal claims; or
you
have objected to the processing based on the grounds described in the next
paragraph below and pending the verification whether we have legitimate grounds
which override your own.
Objecting to Processing.  The GDPR
entitles individuals to object to our processing their personal information for
certain specific purposes (including profiling) where such processing is based
on our legitimate interest. If an individual entitled to do so objects to such
processing we will no longer process their personal information for these
purposes unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for such
processing or such processing is required for the establishment, exercise or
defence of legal claims.
If
personal information is processed by us for direct marketing purposes, individuals
have the right to object at any time to the processing of their personal information
for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related
to such direct marketing.
Lodging Complaints. You have the right to lodge complaints about
the personal information processing activities we carry out before competent supervisory
authorities. We hope though that if you reach out to us first, we can resolve
your complaint amicably.  If not, then
refer to the chart below under "Data Controllers" to
see which supervisory authority to contact.
Email Communications. We use your email address to communicate with
you in order to fulfill any contractual obligations with you (e.g. to send you
invoices or settlement statements) and to notify you about important account
information (e.g. updates to our terms of use or security notices).  These communications are mandatory.  Where permitted by applicable law, we may
send you relevant marketing communications if you have registered and created a
account through one of our websites (including rbauction.com, ironplanet.com,
truckplanet.com, or govplanet.com) and agreed to our terms of use for your
account. We may also send you marketing communications if you have contracted
to sell with us or registered to bid in person at any of our live sales events
and agreed to our terms at the time of registration. In certain jurisdictions,
by doing so, you infer or imply your consent. If you reside in a country that
requires that we obtain your express consent, we will ask for you to expressly
opt-into communications. Marketing communications may come from the Ritchie
Bros. entity that you contracted with when registering an account or
registering to sell or bid, or from another member of the Ritchie Bros. corporate
family that provides products or services that we think may be of interest to
you. If you are receiving marketing emails, you can unsubscribe from these
marketing emails by clicking the unsubscribe link in any marketing email you
receive.
Data sharing with OEMs and their dealers. We provide you with the right to know what
identifiable information and which OEMs and dealers and representatives we have
disclosed information to for their use during the 12-month period preceding the
date of your request.  Depending on where
you live, you may have the right to request data for a greater period of time. To
obtain a list of these OEMs, OEM dealers or representatives who we have disclosed
your identifiable information to and/or to stop any further disclosure, use the privacy contact form or
other options noted above at the beginning of this section.
9. Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences
When
you interact with our online offerings and digital content (e.g. emails or
banner ads) or mobile apps, we, our service providers and selected third
parties may use cookies and similar technologies (e.g. web beacons) to make our
offerings, content and apps better, faster and safer, to personalize our
advertising across the web, or to provide users a personalized experience.
Cookies
are small text files that are automatically created by your browser and stored
on your device when triggered by the online offering or mobile app.  Web beacons operate in conjunction with
cookies as a small imperceptible graphic image that tracks a user action when
taken (e.g. clicking on a link in an email).
Our
use of these technologies falls into four categories:
users to navigate and use functionality of the online offering or mobile app
Functionality
related
Improve
a user’s experience (e.g. remember language preferences, remembering login credentials)
Performance
related
Optimize the operation of the offering (e.g. monitoring load times) or track user interaction to understand usage patterns (e.g. clicks, page views)
Advertising
or targeting related
Deliver personalized experiences, advertising content or emails based on usage patterns and behavior online (a.k.a. re-marketing or re-targeting)
Some
of these technologies may be permanently placed on your device until you remove
them (persistent cookies) while others are temporary and are removed after you
close your browser (session cookies).
Our
service providers use of your data on our behalf is subject to contractual
arrangements between us and them.  When
you take certain actions, or engage with advertisements of our services, on
other websites across the internet, selected third-party organizations place
and use cookies and similar technologies to collect data about your
activities.  This data may be combined
with other data they have acquired and used to profile your interests and serve
you advertisements of interest.  The
processing of your data by these third parties is subject to their privacy
practices over which we have no control.
You
are always free to completely block cookies if your browser or device permits,
although doing so will interfere with your use of some of our websites'
features or content.  Review your browser
settings to do so.
For
more information about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can
opt-out from a range of third parties generally, visit:
Network
Advertising Initiative: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices
U.S.
Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.aboutads.info/choices
Digital
Advertising Alliance of Canada: http://youradchoices.ca
European
Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.youronlinechoices.eu
Note
that using the opt-out tools provided are browser and device specific. As well,
deleting cookies can remove your opt-out preferences, so you will need to
periodically refresh your opt-out preferences.
To
set "Limit Ad Tracking" on various iOS devices, please click here.
To
opt-out of Google interest-based ads on Android, open your Google Settings app
> Ads > Enable "Opt out of interest-based advertising"
Certain
of our service providers allow you to directly limit their ability to target
you with advertising.  Follow their
respective instructions below.  Please
note this list is subject to change.  Contact us as noted at the beginning of this Privacy
Statement for the most up-to-date listing.
by updating your Google Ad Settings. There you will also find instructions to
permanently opt-out through the use of an installed browser plug-in.
Microsoft
Ads (Bing Ads)
Optout
by updating your Microsoft Ad Settings.
Facebook
Ads (including Custom Audiences)
You
may adjust your settings by visiting Facebook's ad preferences page, logging-in and adjusting your settings.
LinkedIn
Ads (including Matched Audiences)
You
may adjust your settings by visiting LinkedIn’s ad settings page, logging-in and adjusting your settings.
Criteo
For
more information about Criteo's privacy practices generally or to opt-out of
further data collection by Criteo, please click here.
Vizury
For
more information about Vizury’s privacy practices generally or to opt-out of
further data collection by Vizury, please click here.
Hotjar
For
more information about Hotjar’s privacy practices generally or to opt-out of
further data collection by Hotjar, please click here.
10. Data Controllers
The
Ritchie Bros. company responsible for the handling of your personal information
depends on the brand you are interacting with and where you are located:
Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Joint Controllers:
Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
Except for RB Logistics services, which are provided by:
Ritchie Bros. B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated EEA Representative:
Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated UK Representative:
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6
IronPlanet
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Joint Controllers:
IronPlanet Limited
Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
IronPlanet
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated EEA Representative:
Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
IronPlanet
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated UK Representative:
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6
Mascus
Any region
Mascus International B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
Mascus
Any region
Designated UK Representative:
Ritchie Bros. UK Limited
One Fleet Place, London England EC4M 7WS
Information Commissioner’s Office
Leake
Any regionNote: Leake Auction hosts auctions only in the United States
Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)
Ritchie Bros. Financial Services
Any region
Note: RBFS services are only available in to the
following regions:  Canada, United States, Australia, Mexico
Ritchie
Bros. Financial Services Ltd.
International B.V.
using our solutions, you may receive or have access to another person's
information.  For example:
While
we do not identify sellers and buyers on the IronPlanet marketplaces, certain
sellers may offer inspection privileges in which case bidders will have access
to name, address and contact information of an equipment manager to arrange for
inspection
Once
a buyer pays for items on the IronPlanet marketplace, they will receive
information about the seller (name, address, contact information) to facilitate
the pick-up of their purchases
Sellers
advertising on the public Mascus marketplace receive the contact information of
interested buyers when an inquiry is made through the contact functionality
Interested
buyers have access to the name and contact information of a seller advertising
an item in a listing on the public Mascus marketplace
You
may use the information received or which you've been given access only to
interact with the other person as part of your transaction or to comply with
regulatory obligations.  You must comply
with all applicable law and, in particular, provide the other person with any
data subject rights to which they are entitled.
You are solely responsible for determining whether you may lawfully use
the information received or accessed for other purposes.  Note that certain information may also be
subject to usage restrictions in accordance with our terms of use or buyer
terms and conditions.
11.2 Providing us with third party personal
information
If
you provide us with personal information relating to another person, you must
obtain the consent of the person or the disclosure of the information to us
must be otherwise legally permissible. You must inform the other person of how
we process personal data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.
11.3 Children's privacy
Our
solutions are not intended for use by children.
We do not knowingly collect information from users or participants who
are considered children under applicable laws.
To participate in an auction or use our services, you must be 18 or
older.
11.4 Logging in to IronPlanet's online
marketplaces using your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers web account
We
permit you to use your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers online web account credentials
to log in to IronPlanet's online marketplaces.
To facilitate this cross-solution authentication, when you register an
account with Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers, we automatically create a dormant
account for you on IronPlanet that becomes active only when you first sign-in.
11.5 Logging in to a preferred provider's site
using Ritchie Bros. credentials
We
permit certain of our preferred partners to authenticate your online access to
their website or webservices using your IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
online credentials.  If you choose to do
so, when logging-in you will be redirected to our website to enter your credentials.  Once you successfully login, you will be
redirected again back to the partner's site. Your personal information
collected by the partner when using their site will be handled by them for the
purposes they disclose to you (such as in their privacy notices).
11.6 Links and Social Media Presences
Our
websites contain links to other sites including sites maintained by our
customers, third party service providers or preferred or recommended providers.
We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage
our users to read the privacy notices of all websites they choose to visit that
collect personal information.
Ritchie
Bros. maintains publicly accessible profiles in various social networks listed
below. Our social media presence ensures an internet presence that is as
comprehensive as possible – which supports our legitimate commercial and
marketing interests.
Social
networks are able to analyze your user behaviour when you visit their websites
or other sites with integrated social media plug-ins, or you use their mobile
apps.  When you're logged-in to your
social media account and you visit our social media presence, or you click on a
hyperlink to our social media presence and then log-in to your account, the
social media operator associates your visit with your social media user
account.  It may also be possible for the
operator to identify you when you are not logged-in or do not have an
account.  All of this is made possible by
the placement of tracking tools on your browser or device that are associated
with the social media operator.  These
allow the operator to receive information from our websites which it combines
with information it receives elsewhere on the internet or from other sources.
Social
media operators use the information gathered about you to create user profiles
that store your preferences and interests.
The profiles are used to tailor advertising to you based on your
interests both within and outside of their respective social media sites and
across any device you've used to access the social media site.  The information is also used by operators to
provide anonymous measurement statistics and demographic data to us as
administrators of our social media presence.
We use this data to create content more relevant to our target audiences.  For details of other uses of this data by
operators, please refer to their respective privacy notices. For further
information about our collection of data using cookies, web beacons and similar
tools when you interact with our digital services, check out "Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences".
For
individuals with rights under the GDPR, when you visit one our social media
presences, we are jointly responsible as controllers together with the social
media operator for the data processing activities triggered by your visit.  You may assert your rights against either of
us, but please note, despite having joint responsibility we have no real
influence over the data processing activities conducted by the social media
operator.  Refer to the information below
for the specifics of each social media operator.
Social Media Presence
Provider
Important Info.
Facebook
Fanpages
Facebook
Ireland Limited
4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour,
Dublin 2 Ireland
The following agreement governs our joint responsibility for processing: https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum
You can set
your advertising preferences vi your user account.  Click below and login: https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads
Inc.
1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA
For
details on the processing of your information by Instagram, review to its
adjust your Twitter data privacy settings independently via your user account.
To do so, click on this link and log in: https://twitter.com/personalization
For further
details please refer to the Twitter privacy policy:
your advertising preferences independently via your user account. To do so,
click on this link and log in: https://myaccount.google.com/intro/data-and-personalization
following agreement governs our joint responsibility for processing: https://legal.linkedin.com/pages-joint-controller-addendum
If you would
like to deactivate LinkedIn advertising cookies, please use the following link: https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out
For details of how your personal data are
processed, please refer to the LinkedIn privacy policy: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy
11.7 Regional disclosures
This
Privacy Statement establishes our global principles for the collection, use,
disclosure and storage of personal information that is processed by Ritchie
Bros. member companies in the course of our operations.  Certain places where you are doing business
with us or where the website or application you are interacting with is located
or hosted may have specific requirements concerning personal information which
may be found under our State Privacy
Disclosures.
Contact Ian Malinski: CorpComm@rbauction.com or 778.331.5432.
Media information on rbauction.com
Investors
Contact Sameer Rathod: ir@ritchiebros.com or 510.381.7584.
Investor information on rbauction.com
© 2020 Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
|
Privacy Statement | Do not sell my information | Legal Notices
